前情提要
-受害者是谁 -爱迪生·姚 中国人 在公寓里被暗杀
- Who's your victim? - Edison Yao. Chinese national. Assassinated in his apartment.
他的公寓中装满监控录像 但枪手却不见踪影
He had CCTV all over the flat, only the shooters are nowhere to be seen.
我想你可能会提供一些 见解
I thought you might have some...insight.
我做不到 对不起
I can't do this, I'm sorry.
我懂 打不过就加入 对吧
No, I get it. Can't beat 'em, join 'em, right?
赞达面部识别
Xanda Facial Recognition.
世界上唯一能以100%的准确率
The only security system in the world
识别人脸的安全系统
to identify a human face with 100% accuracy.
中国的人工智能技术不构成威胁
Chinese AI technology poses no threat.
是的 我读过宣传稿 抱歉 是新闻稿
Yeah, I read the propaganda - sorry, press release.
只要我还是安全大臣 英国的边境安全就不会
As long as I'm Security Minister, Britain's borders won't be monitored
落到中国这种门面企业手中
by a storefront for the People's Republic of China.
长官 我有发现
Ma'am? I've got something.
闭路电视中有些 猫腻
CCTV threw up some...concerns.
-跟我们的专业相关 -把监控发过来
- Our kind of concerns. - Pass on the details.
我会派人去看看的
I'll assign someone to take a look.
加兰德仍然不信任我
Garland doesn't trust me, still.
我是自愿加入的
I signed up to be part of this.
这位拉各斯的护工声称 她三岁儿子的父亲
The Lagos care worker claims her three-year-old son's father
是英国安全大臣艾萨克·特纳
is Britain's Security Minister, Isaac Turner.
什么 这都是赞达干的
What?! This is them. This is Xanda.
特纳先生 如果我们真要插手
If we wanted to meddle, Mr Turner,
你认为我们就这点手段
do you think this is the best we can do?
下午好 尊敬的
Good afternoon, distinguished members
各位中国研究委员会成员
of the China Research Committee,
还有格雷戈里
and Gregory.
拍板投票的人没来全
Not everybody is present for the final vote.
爱迪生去哪儿
Where is Edison?
死者的最后活动是拨打电话
The victim's last activity was an attempted call.
也许他是想警告什么人
Maybe he was trying to warn someone.
-打给谁的 -手机联系人为诺克斯
- Caller ID? - Saved on the phone as Knox.
格雷戈里·诺克斯吗 大楼里有武装入侵者 进去
Gregory Knox? There are armed intruders in the building. Get in.
不 我没有加入他们
No, I haven't joined them,
我是要打败他们
I am trying to beat them!
他们日日夜夜监视看我
And they are watching me day and night!
委员会那边情况如们
What's the status with the committee?
所有人员都转移至安全屋
All assets are in safe houses.
在我看来 我们带这些人去安全屋正中他们下怀
For all we know, the safe houses are exactly where they want us to take these people!
在我旁边的是安全大臣艾萨克·特纳
Well, I'm now joined by Home Office Security Minister Isaac Turner.
晚上好 哈迪亚
Good evening, Khadija.
这就是他们设计你来这里的原因
This is it, the reason they wanted you.
我认为正确的做法 是把英国边境合同
I believe the right decision is to award the UK borders contract
授予赞达面部识别公司
to Xanda Facial Recognition.
我们的安全 我们的生活方式
..our security or our way of life.
这个决定会让很多人大吃一惊
This decision will come as a surprise to those who see you
这些人曾把你当做中国在英基建投资的强大对手
as a strong opponent to China's investment in UK infrastructure.
哈迪亚 我一向兼收并蓄
Oh, Khadija, I've always maintained I keep an open mind.
他在干什么啊
What is he doing?!
不知道 他说的都是赞达新闻稿的内容
I don't know. He's literally quoting Xanda's press release.
我的手机快打爆了 《卫报》催我回应
My phones are exploding, Guardian's hounding me for a follow-up,
-他都还没下节目呢 -他跟你说什么了吗
- he isn't even off air! - Did he say anything to you?
他说过要为他曾坪击的间谋公司背书吗
Did he say anything about endorsing the company he accused of spying?
他一定吓坏了 爱迪生被杀了 诺克斯又被的上
He must be scared. Edison's been killed, Knox has been targeted.
等等 天啊 是他老婆打来的
Oh, Christ, his wife's calling. Wait.
西蒙妮艾丽莎 你在看吗
Simone? Aliza, are you watching this?
在看 你还好吗
Yeah. Are you OK?
我还好 家里都有警察
Yeah, I think so. We've got police here.
-你为什么这么问 -没事 我们也看不明白
- Why are you asking?  - No, it's just, we don't get it either.
对不起 西蒙妮 我过会儿给你回申
Sorry, Simone, can I call you back?
该项目还没有经过种族歧视的测试
The programme hasn't been tested for racial bias.
遗憾的是 涉及到不同肤色的人种时
Sadly, there are a number of facial rec systems that underperform
很多面部识别系统都表现不佳
when it comes to accurately identifying people of colour,
这完全是不可接受的
which is totally unacceptable, of course.
他是不是脑子进水了
Has he had a stroke?
格雷戈里 你不是该待在安全屋吗
Gregory! Shouldn't you be in a safe house?
对 我求看警察让我用他们的电话打过来的
I am. I had to plead with the police to let me use their phone.
持纳不是告诉内政部 我们一致反对赞达的吗
I thought Turner told the Home Sec we unanimously opposed to Xanda?
他估计是害怕了
We think he's scared.
防止种族定性的办法
The way to safeguard against racial profiling
就是选择准确率最高的识别系统
is to choose a recognition system that's virtually 100% accurate.
赞达能让我们安心
And Xanda gives us that peace of mind.
他看起来一点也不害怕
He doesn't look scared.
如果你们不打算去BBC找出原因
If you're refusing to March down to the BBC and get some answers...
-我坚持 -我就就自己去
- I must insist... - ..I will do it myself!
你必须待在一级防范封锁区
..insist you stay on lockdown!
扎克 你认识哈特指挥官吧
Zach? You know Commander Hart.
内政大臣 吉玛
Home Secretary.  Gemma.
-你也看了对吧 -《新闻之夜》吗
- You were watching, then?  - Newsnight?
我要是想看政府洋相百出
If I wanted to watch the Government get its teeth kicked in,
就去出席首相问答了
I'd turn up to PMQs.
-你一定很震惊吧 大臣 -震惊
- Must have been a shock, Minister. - A shock?
不完全是 丹尼
No, not quite, Danny.
看到自己上电视可以称得上震惊
Turning on the TV to see yourself on a normal day is a shock.
但打开电视 看到不是自己的自己
Turning on the TV to see yourself when it's not yourself,
说着与自己的信念背道而驰的话
saying the exact opposite of what you fundamentally believe
是他妈的精神强奸 我实话实说了
is a fucking mind-rape, if you want to know the truth.
吉玛
Gemma?
我们是不是需要 做好保密工作
Do you think we need to, um...pull up the drawbridge?
拉提夫督查 凯莉总督察 出去等待进一步指示
DI Latif, DCI Carey, await further instruction outside.
-长官 -对了
- Ma'am, I...  - On second thoughts,
凯莉总督察 你不用等了 你被解雇了
DCI Carey, you don't need to wait, you're dismissed.
Report to Mapping per your regular duties first thing.
你的决定很有趣啊
That's an interesting decision.
-你说什么 -是你把我关到这里
- I'm sorry?  - You were the one who put me on lockdown,
这正是他们想要的
which is exactly what they wanted.
凯莉警探是唯一一个
Detective Carey is the only one
看出问题的人
who managed to fathom something was wrong here.
鉴于凯莉对全局的理解 也许她该留下
Perhaps DCI Carey should stay, given she's fully conversant.
我们要怎么办
What are we going to do?
多亏了 这个 荒唐的闹剧
Thanks to this...whatever it is,
整个国家现在都觉得
the nation is now under the impression
我愿意把面部识别外包给
that I'm happy to farm out facial rec
策划了这一切的外国敌对势力
to the same hostile foreign power that orchestrated this.
你确信这是中国的手笔
You're convinced China's responsible?
北京要试图干预英国的政策
Beijing is trying to meddle in British policy.
严王磊是赞达在伦敦的老大
Yan Wanglei is Xanda's man in London.
他绝对参与其中了 我很确定
He's a part of it, I'm certain.
显然 我们需要召开危机应对会议
We need to call a COBRA meeting, obviously.
情报部和国防部需要马上起草方案
SIS and the MoD should begin drafting options immediately.
先形成一版方案制定对策
We'll need a raft to formulate our response,
但最重要的是 我要去一趟
but first and foremost, I would like to pay a visit
BBC广播大厦
to Broadcasting House.
我试过拖住他了
I managed to delay him.
我们不想让你去是有原因的 艾萨克
There's a reason I can't let you do that, Isaac.
如果你跑去BBC
If you go running off to the BBC,
新闻肯定会铺天盖地的
it'll end up all over the news.
对 罗文 我也希望能做出澄清
Yes, Rowan, I was rather hoping it might.
你来决定吧 内政大臣
Your decision, Home Secretary.
我觉得最好澄清下
Well, I think we'd better.
这家伙承受了太多
Poor bloke's been through enough.
我们要提醒您 先生 作为一名政府大臣
We ought to remind you, sir, that as a Government minister,
你得遵守《官员保密法)
you are bound by the Official Secrets Act.
抱歉 有人能好心告诉我
I'm sor... Is someone kindly going to tell me
你们到底在说什么吗
what the hell you're all talking about?
好的
Yes.
让凯莉总督察来解释吧
DCI Carey can explain it...
鉴于她完全了解全局
..given she's fully conversant.
来吧 瑞秋 我们都坐稳了
Come on, Rachel, we're all sitting comfortably.
你来给特纳先生上一堂
Why don't you tell Mr Turner everything he needs to know...
关于「移花接木」的课吧
..about Correction?
明天同一时间再见
We'll be back, of course, same time tomorrow.
在那之前 祝大家晚安
Until then, from all of us, goodnight.
完毕
We're clear.
特纳的来访在推特上引起轩然大波
The Turner interview is causing a sizeable Twitter storm.
绝对没料到他会那么说
Certainly wasn't expecting him to say that.
#艾萨克墙头草
#Isaacturncoat.
他在想什么呢
What was he thinking?!
我有预感 这个新闻我们会继续跟进
I have a feeling we'll be following this one up.
下次让他来演播室
Try to get him into the studio next time.
我受够这些远程采访了 你明白我的意思吗
Remote interviews depress me these days. Do you know what I mean?
信号像90年代那样断断续续 一直延迟
Uh-huh.  It might help if they didn't lag and freeze like it was 1996!
-不该有延迟的啊 -艾德 但你看到延迟了
- There shouldn't be any lagging. - Ed, you saw the lagging, right?
对啊 当然
Yeah, absolutely.
整个节目怎么感觉只有我一个人在操心
Sometimes I think I'm the only one actually watching around here.
-不应该有延迟的 -去调查下 好吗
- There shouldn't be any lagging. - Have a look into it, will you?
所以我的遭遇 它还有个名字
So, it has a name, what happened to me?
「移花接木」 是一种实时图像处理的方法
Correction...is a method of real-time image manipulation,
通过干扰摄像头信号
using the disruption of camera feeds
■
深度伪造
该技术实际在github上
是开源的，所有人都可
以免费获取并使用。
的深度伪造技术来实现
and the deployment of deepfake technology.
"这项技术由中国开发"
The technique was developed in China,
但是它的应用已经扩展到
but its usage has spread to...
世界其它地区
..other regions.
哪些地区
What regions?
地区在不断扩大 但可以肯定的是
The map is constantly evolving, but it's safe to assume
「移花接木」技术已经扩展到了俄罗斯 美国
Correction is in operation in Russia, United States...
和英国
The United Kingdom.
怎么会扩展到这里
Why would it be in operation here?
比如 如果我们收到人恐怖分子的情报
For instance, if we have intel on a terrorist plot,
但对嫌犯的起诉证据还不够
but the evidence against the suspects is insufficient.
如果你们无法合法地收集到证据
If you can't put them away fair and square,
就会伪造犯罪录像
you fake incriminating footage?
我们会把情报变成证据
We turn intelligence into evidence.
这事都谁知道
Who knows about this?
这是一种高度保密的作战方法
It's a highly-restricted operational tactic.
仅限反恐指挥部 政府通讯总部和安全局特工知道 不超过50人
No more than 50 operatives across SO15, GCHQ and the Security Service.
但还有谁 司法大臣 首相知道吗
But who else? The Justice Secretary? The PM?
我无法问答你的问题
You know I can't confirm or deny.
英国政府在生产深伪技术
The British state creating deep fakes?
我们只生产我们知道是真实事件的图像
We only ever produce images of events we know to be true.
这...
This is... Huh!
不 不 不 这不可能
No. No, no, no, this isn't happening.
我插一句 这项目不是在我任期内开始
If it makes a difference, this did not start on my watch.
这碗道德大乱炖是我的前任留下来的
This moral minestrone was gifted to me by my predecessor.
所以为什么是我
So, why me?
他们选我是为了什么
Where does this aberration come into it?
因为能够生成权势人物的虚假形象
Sadly, with the means to create false images of powerful people,
「移花接木」技术已成为造谣的工具
Correction has become a tool for disinformation.
我们跟对手都在使用这种肮脏的技术
Correction is the dirty secret we share with our adversaries.
彼此心照不宣
We can all deploy it covertly,
但如果一个国家跳出来公开指责另一方
but if one country accuses another publicly,
我们就跟自爆无异
we may as well blow the whistle on ourselves.
你什么意思
So, what are you saying?
如果我们捅出有人「移花接木」了你的视频
If we were to claim your appearance was corrected,
别人也可以同样捅出我们
it would leave us vulnerable to counter-accusations.
然后整个世界的纸牌屋都会坍塌
And then, the whole global house of cards comes tumbling down.
你们 想让我闭嘴
You...you expect me to keep my mouth shut
让全世界相信这番鬼话是真的
and let the world believe that malicious bullshit was real?
抱歉 艾萨克 姚已经死了
I'm sorry, Isaac. Edison Yao is dead!
他们在杀害不同政见者 攻击我们的全国广播
They are killing dissidents and attacking our national broadcasts!
这是国家支持的恐怖行动
These are acts of state-sponsored terror!
我们会为此采取适当的行动的
For which, appropriate action will be taken.
只要不捅出什么恐怖项目就行
So long as it doesn't upset some spook programme?!
只要不影响政府
So long as it doesn't upset the Government,
法院 军情五处和警方
the courts, MI5 and the police.
听懂了吗
Good enough?
希望我们可以相信这位南哈斯米尔的议员
Let's hope we can rely on the Right Honourable Member
能保守住秘密
for Haslemere South to keep his trap shut.
我们要看管好艾萨克·特纳 封闭保护警员
We keep Isaac Turner on a short leash. Close protection officers,
拦截和监控所有设备
intercepts and monitoring on all devices.
包括他的员工 他们安排了那次采访
Same goes for his staff. They arranged that interview.
其中也可能有人是同谋
Any one of them could be complicit.
你见过那样的「移花接木」吗
Do you see Correction like that?
■
索尔兹伯里
指2018年谢尔盖和尤利
娅·斯克里帕尔中毒案
特纳说得对 我们面对的是自索尔兹伯里以来
Turner's right, we're looking at the most blatant attack
外国势力是最严重的袭击
by a foreign power since Salisbury.
-你需要什么资源 -秘密团队 反恐指挥部 政府通讯部和中情局的全力支持
- What do you need?  - Tight team, SO15, GCHQ and CIA to support.
你想团队里都有谁
Who do you want on your team?
瑞秋让特纳印象深刻
Rachel certainly made an impression on Turner.
拉他加入我们也挺好
Wouldn't hurt to keep him onside.
看来你忘了她差点就要举报我们了
You seem to forget how close she came to reporting us.
那是在你说服她之前
That was before you won her over.
更别说我们发现了什么
Not to mention what we found.
这是保险的做法 你也会这么做的
That was insurance. You'd do the same.
有人监视着她吧
She's being watched, isn't she?
还有什么担心吗
Any concerns?
如果你还是不信任她 杰玛 你知道该怎么做
If you still don't trust her, Gemma, you know what to do.
观察好她
Keep her close.
我需要一名总督察作反恐部门和凶杀组的联络人
I'll need a DCI to bridge Homicide and SO15.
-有兴趣吗 -有 长官
- If you're interested?  - I am, Ma'am.
你需要助手 你看中谁了
You'll need assistance. What do you make of the new blood?
谭警员
DC Tan?
几年前 他们还会称我为快速通道公主呢
Couple of years ago, they'd have called her fast-track princess.
他们也叫过我 具体叫我什么就不说了
They did me. I won't repeat what they called me.
拉蒂夫督查 你让安全屋暴露在危险中
DI Latif, you have compromised the location of a safe house.
这种违反安全的行为 可能要受到纪律处分
A security breach that may warrant disciplinary action.
但是长官 我虽还未做出决定
But, Ma'am, I... While a decision is pending,
但禁止你参与这次行动 即刻生效
your inclusion in this operation is suspended with immediate effect.
你可以回到原单位继续履职
You may return to your departmental duties,
但这里不需要你了
but your time with us ends here.
就感谢你的处罚没那么严重吧
Be thankful the repercussions aren't more severe.
带上谭警员一起
Bring DC Tan in with you.
去哪儿 长官
In where, Ma'am?
7楼
Seventh floor.
地图部门呢
What about Mapping?
地图部门自己就能运行
Mapping runs itself.
你一直想要我的案子
Well, you WANTED to take over my case.
终于得偿所愿了
Got what you wished for.
我是总督察瑞秋·凯莉
This is DCI Rachel Carey.
进行隐藏摄像拍摄
In place of hidden camera recording,
拍摄此视频是要实名举报
I'm filming this eyewitness testimony for my dossier
详细记录了系统性的
detailing the systematic illegal practice
非法算改视频证据的行为 即「移花接木」
of video-evidence tampering known as Correction.
大约一小时前
Approximately one hour ago,
我出席了内政大臣罗文·吉尔的简报会
I was present at a briefing with Home Secretary Rowan Gill,
了解到「移花接木」的所有内情
who I learned has full knowledge of Correction
以及其在英国的应用
and its use within the UK.
同时出席的还有安全大臣艾萨克·特纳 他
Also present was the Security Minister Isaac Turner, who...
在简报会之前 对「移花接木」全然不知情
..until the briefing, had no prior knowledge of Correction.
你之前为什么不给我打电话
Why couldn't you call me before?
涉及机密
Er...security.
警方要求的
Police insisted.
所以 你可以上《新闻之夜》跟哈迪亚·汗大谈特谈
So, you can go on Newsnight and talk to Khadija Khan,
却不能打给你妻子
but you can't call your wife?
我没
I wasn't...
我没上《新闻之夜》
I wasn't on Newsnight.
你知道我什么意思
You know what I mean.
远程控制
Remotely.
你为什么改主意了
Why did you change your mind?
关于面部识别合同的事
About the facial-rec contract?
我不能说 西蒙
I can't talk about it, Simmy.
对了 你说的是"肤色不同的人"
You said "people of colour", by the way.
我以为你不喜欢这个词呢
I thought you didn't like that phrase?
你总说它听起来太像"有色人种"
You always said it sounded too close to "coloured people".
不过你做得很好
You did good, though,
采访里
in the interview.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
不是你说的那些话 而是
Not what you said, just...
你说话的方式
..the way you said it.
你听起来 很权威
You sounded...authoritative.
我想听真话 艾萨克
I want the truth, Isaac.
那些要杀了格雷戈里·诺克斯的人
The people who tried to kill Gregory Knox...
-也会想杀你吗 -不会
- ..are they going to try to kill you? - No. No, no.
说实话
The truth.
我不知道
I don't know.
事实证明 我不知道的事有很多
Turns out there's a lot I don't know.
先锋行动的首要任务如下
The priorities of Operation Vanguard are as follows.
调查过去的36小时里在首都发生的
To investigate a series of targeted assassinations
一系列有针对性的暗杀行动
across the capital in the past 36 hours,
确定主要嫌疑犯
to identify the prime suspects
收集针对英国监控网络
and to gather intelligence on a campaign of cyberattacks
以及一家主流电视广播公司的
against UK surveillance networks
网络攻击行动的情报
and a major television broadcaster.
这次对英国基础设施和平民的公然攻击
This blatant attack on UK infrastructure and civilians
是我见过的最令人发指的袭击之一
is one of the most heinous I've come across.
不仅仅是因为他们伤害了我们的同僚
Not least because they've hurt one of our own.
根据我们的评估 这一连串的袭击
It is our assessment that this chain of attacks
与BBC遭受的黑客攻击有关
was coordinated with a hack on the BBC
是外国故对势力企图影响政府决策的阴谋
in a plot to affect government policy by a hostile foreign power.
在搜寻谋杀嫌疑人的过程中
While the trawl for any trace of the murder suspects continues,
特纳本人提醒我们要注意这个嫌疑人
Turner himself alerted us to this person of interest.
作为赞达面部识别系统驻伦敦首席执行官
As London CEO of Xanda Facial Rec,
严王磊动机充分且具备技术能力
Yan Wanglei has the motive and the technical capability.
考虑到他是位备受瞩目的中国公民
Now, given his status as a high-profile Chinese national,
应该无需我告诉各位侦办此案要有多谨慎
I need hardly tell you how carefully we need to tread here.
任何逮捕行动都将构成重大国际事件
Any arrest will constitute a major international incident.
但不必误会 如若证据确凿
But make no mistake, we will arrest him
我们会将他缉捕归案
if that's where the evidence leads us.
我们今天上午很恭敬的联系了王磊先生
We've reached out respectfully to Mr Wanglei this morning,
他答应接受我们的询问
and he's accepted our invitation to be questioned.
前提是要在中国大使馆里进行
Provided it takes place at the Chinese Embassy
并要求晓东大使在场
in the presence of Ambassador Xiaodong.
有人要猜猜犯罪嫌疑人现在的位置吗
Anyone care to guess the POI's current location?
中国大使馆吗
Chinese Embassy?
谢天谢地你终于来了 凯莉
Thank God you're here, Carey, finally.
没错 他在大使馆里
Yes, he's tucked away at the embassy.
就依他要求 我会去拜访大使
Let's take him up on his offer. I'll pay the ambassador a visit.
如果是北京方面授意 那就有合理的理由怀疑他是同谋
If this came from Beijing, there's reasonable grounds he's complicit.
我可以一并去大使馆
I could come...to the embassy...
如果有帮助的话
..if it helps.
你会说普通话吗
Do you speak Mandarin?
不会
No.
只会说几句
A couple of words.
那为什么
Then, why...?
只是
Well...just...
会不会能起到点...
Isn't that a bit...?
我觉得是个好主意 谭警员
I think that's a good idea, DC Tan.
-克洛伊 -我需要支持
- Chloe.  - I'll need the support.
同意 失陪
Agreed. Excuse me.
瑞秋
Rachel?
对中国来说 就像是1939年把英国的雷达合同
..to China was like handing a British radar contract
交给德国一样
to Germany in 1939.
我做过调查 没发现赞达同中国当局之间
I've done my research, I found no evidence of a link between Xanda
有联系
and the Chinese authorities.
作为英国安全大臣 我完全支持中研委的
As Britain's Security Minister, I fully support the CRC's...
通过摄像头进行远程采访 罪犯要做的就是
Remote interview via webcam. All the perps would need to do is
把他们的消息发给BBC
pipe in their feed to the BBC.
所有远程摄像头都有可能被黑客入侵
Any remote camera has the potential to be hacked.
与主机无缝交互
Interaction with the host, seamless.
你怀疑她与此事有关
You suspect her involvement?
大人说话的时候
Isn't it customary to send the kids to bed
不是该让小孩上床睡觉去吗
when the grown-ups are talking?
凯莉总督察和我们一样有权待在这里
DCI Carey has the same right to be here as any of us.
你具体想说什么 哈迪亚·汗是同谋吗
What are you saying exactly - Khadija Khan is complicit?
或者说虚拟形象可以实时回答她的问题
Or the avatar can respond to her questions in real time?
有可能构建这种深伪技术吗
Is it possible to create a deepfake that sophisticated?
我们的技术还没达到
Hmm? Oh. Well...we haven't gotten there yet.
要能做出来的话 也是中国有这能力
If anyone has, it's China.
我很乐意告诉你们怎么去他们大使馆
I'd love to furnish you with directions to their embassy.
既然你能黑进主机 干嘛还走大门
Why use the front door when you can hack the mainframe?
抱歉 我帮不了你
Oh, sorry, I can't help you there.
你说什么 行政部门下的禁制令
Beg your pardon?  Strict orders from the executive branch.
情报机构不能再协助针对中华人民共和国的
The agency can no longer assist in third-party counter-espionage
第三方反间谍活动
against the People's Republic of China.
-为什么不行 -因为你和他们做了太多生意
- Why the hell not?!  - Because you do too much business with them,
就因为这个 我当初跟你说别跟北京纠缠不清的时候
that's why! When we tell you not to get into bed with Beijing,
你充耳不闻
you bury deeper into the sheets!
所以 是因为钱喽
So, this is about money?
是为了安全
It's about security!
我们和英国分享了很多情报
You know, we share a lot of intel with the UK.
我想知道中国并不知情
I'd like to know that China isn't listening.
有留言 长官 安东尼·里德让你联系他
Message for you, ma'am. Anthony Reid asked that you contact him.
他说是急事
Oh.  He says it's urgent.
-安东尼·里德 -对
- Anthony Reid?  - Yes.
THE Anthony Reid?  Yes.
-那他妈是谁啊 -BBC的安全记者
- Who the fuck's that? - Security correspondent for the BBC.
不可能是巧合
It can't be a coincidence.
-反正我们也要查到那步的对吧 -我本指望
- Surely we need to investigate there anyway?  - I was hoping
这事儿能尽可能久地远离媒体
to keep this away from the press for as long as humanly possible.
我想留下来
Well, I'd like to stick around.
等你的国家学会怎么选边站的时候再打给我
Give me a call when your country learns how to pick a side.
弗兰克
Frank?!
听着 如果你需要技术支持去对付BBC
Frank!
Look, if you need technical help with the BBC,
我可以借给你我的一个人
I'll loan you one of my guys.
但要是让我发现你把技术用来对付中国 交易取消
But if I find out you put them on China, the deal's off.
弗兰克·纳皮尔什么时候开始听从政客发号施令了
Since when did Frank Napier let politicians call the shots?
自打我发现他们在监视我
Since I found out they were watching me.
长官
Ma'am?
就像全球成千上万的签证申请者一样
Like thousands of visa applicants around the globe,
维多利亚·贝洛梦想在英国生活和工作
Victoria Bello dreams of living and working in the UK.
昨天 里斯·爱德华兹收到了这封邮件
This landed in Rhys Edwards' inbox yesterday.
护理人员声称她三岁的儿子
..care worker claims her three-year-old son
有资格申请英国护照
is eligible for a British passport.
据维多利亚说 孩子的父亲
According to Victoria, the child's father
是英国安全大臣 艾萨克·特纳
is Britain's Security Minister, Isaac Turner.
-这事曝光了吗 -网上还没踪迹
- Has this gone public? - No trace of it online.
根据随之而来的信息轰炸
According to the message frenzy that followed,
特纳似平认为这是赞达方面的敲诈勒系
Turner seemed to think it was some kind of blackmail attempt by Xanda.
我想知道他为什么没跟我们提起过
I'd like to know why he didn't mention that to us.
我也是这想法
My thoughts exactly.
长官
Ma'am?
请他进来
Invite him in.
派配枪警官保护
Under armed protection.
也给他员工派上
Same goes for his staff.
这就是奇迹发生的地方么
So, this is where the magic happens?
他们是怎么说服你的
How DID they get you?
说服我
Get me?
瑞秋
Rachel?
里斯·爱德华兹
Rhys Edwards?
为了更安全的不列颠
哈特指挥官
Commander Hart.
大使 感谢您拨冗
Ambassador. Thank you for taking the time.
这位是谭警员
This is Detective Tan.
很高兴见到您
Pleased to meet you.
请 客人已经在等着了
Hmm! Please, our guest is waiting.
您好像很久都没有
Seems a long time since you threw
办过晚宴了 大使
one of your famous soirees, Ambassador.
怎么不办了呀
Whatever happened to those?
你们国家指控我国种族火绝
Your country accused us of genocide.
没毛病
Fair enough.
爱迪生·姚是香港的持不同政见者
Edison Yao was a dissident from Hong Kong.
大约36小时前 有人去到他公寓
About 36 hours ago, someone came to his apartment
朝他眼睛开了一枪
and put a bullet through his eye.
他现在怎么样
How is he now?
太可怕了
That's awful,
但麻烦你解释一下 这和我有什么关系
but would you mind explaining what it has to do with me?
姚先生曾在中研委任职
Mr Yao served on the China Research Committee,
就贵公司的面部识别投标项目做过政府顾问
advising the Government on your company's facial recognition bid.
24小时后 保安约瑟夫·姆旺吉颈部中弹
24 hours later, security guard Joseph Mwangi was shot in the neck
一位警长胸部中枪
and a police detective sergeant was shot in the chest.
他们也都是中国研究委员会的成员吗
Were they on the China Research Committee?
我们相信目标人物是
We believe the intended target was.
一位名叫格雷戈里·诺克斯的数据科学家
A data scientist named Gregory Knox.
每起案件中 子弹都是从 QSZ-92自动步枪上射出的
In each case, the bullet was discharged from a QSZ-92 automatic.
一种中国大陆制造的军用武器
A military-issue firearm manufactured in mainland China.
在英国发现中国制造的产品并不出奇
No surprise to find products in the UK made in China.
是不奇怪 尤其是涉及到技术设备 电脑
No, not when it comes to technology. Computers...
-金属 矿物塑料 -医疗设备
- Metal, minerals, plastics. - Medical equipment.
但军用武器 这就不多见了
But military-grade weapons? That's rare.
中国不会报复持不同政见者
China does not take revenge on its dissidents
也不会在英国大街上追捕他们 我们不是俄罗斯
and hunt them down on the streets of Britain. We are not Russia.
没人说是报复
No-one mentioned revenge.
我忘了恭喜二位了
I forgot to congratulate you both.
看起来你们很快就能签下面部识别的合同了
Looks like the facial-rec contract is going your way.
我很好奇
I'm curious.
你觉得为什么一位以反中国科技而闻名的大臣
Why do you think a minister known for his stance against Chinese tech
最后会跟一家中国企业合作
ended up going with a Chinese company?
你知道你在暗示什么吗 小姐
Do you realise what you're implying, young lady?
谭警员
DC Tan.
只是问问
Just asking.
真令人失望
How very disappointing.
再一次 我们发现自己成为
Once again, we find ourselves
毫无根据 耸人听闻的指控对象
the subject of baseless, lurid allegations.
中国 世界上最可怕的国家
China, the bogeyman of the world.
我们觉得这样很无礼
We find it offensive.
就如同我们也觉得有件事很无礼 哈特指挥官
Just as we find it offensive, Commander Hart,
就是你带了一个华裔同事
that you bring along a colleague of Chinese descent
来中和你厚颜无耻的偏见
to appease your brazen prejudice.
我还有别的事
I have another engagement.
也许等你不带偏见
Perhaps we could continue this
且有更多证据之后 我们再谈吧
when you have something more to go on besides bias?
I'm sorry to hear about your detective sergeant.
You said he was shot, but you didn't say if he survived.
我是没说
No, I didn't.
汤姆 我要一队人全天侯监视入口
Tom, I want a team car watching the entrance 24/7.
我来指派人员
I'll assign the eyeball.
你觉得加入监视小组怎么样
How do you feel about joining a surveillance unit?
长官 除了快速通道上的摸排 我没什么监视经验
Sir, apart from basic undercover on the fast-track, I don't have much
但你近距离接触过目标
experience.  Yeah, but you've seen the target up close and personal.
调度和监控
Ops and monitoring.
我们需要核实 盯住严王磊
We need verification. Eyes on Yan Wanglei.
长官
Sir.
关于纳迪亚 长官
About Nadia, Ma'am...
拉蒂夫督察
DI Latif.
她不会真的被纪律处分吧
She's not actually going to receive disciplinary action, is she?
因为她只是听我指示才闯进的安全屋
Because she only breached the safe house on my instruction.
要是你有这闲工夫去内疚
If you have the spare time or the bandwidth to feel guilty about it,
why don't you give her a call?
最好再送束花
Better yet, send flowers.
同时 我希望你能集中注意力
In the meantime, I'd appreciate your focus.
是 长官
Yes, Ma'am.
你打算怎么办 长官
So, how do you want to play this, then, Ma'am?
多动耳朵 多学习
Just listen and learn.
-杰姆 -安东尼
- Gem!  - Anthony!
谢谢你来找我们
Thank you for coming to us.
我订好了地方
I've booked somewhere we can't be overlooked.
我想你已经看过艾萨克·特纳的采访了
I imagine you've seen the Isaac Turner interview.
他现在支持赞达了
He's pro-Xanda now.
对 即使以本届政府标准来看 这个反转也相当令人惊讶
Yes. Pretty surprising U-turn, even by this Government's standards.
让我们不禁怀疑中国是否有了特纳的把柄
Got us wondering if China has something on Turner.
直到我们偶然发现了一个不同的理论
Until we chanced upon a different theory.
哈迪亚昨晚抱怨过远程连接速度太慢了
Khadija complained about the remote connection speed last night.
这倒没什么可奇怪的
Nothing odd about that.
哈迪亚大多数晚上都会抱怨点事
Khadija complains about something MOST nights.
但当工程师们追踪特纳的IP地址时
But when the engineers tracked Turner's IP address,
他们发现了一些奇怪的东西
they discovered something strange.
信号不是伦敦发出的
The signal wasn't coming from London.
其至都不是从英国发出来的
Wasn't coming from the UK at all.
是从中国发出来的
It was coming from China.
要分享一些见解吗
Care to share any insights?
你们将此事告知我们是正确的
You're right to bring this to our attention.
我建议安排专人小组进行调香
I suggest we arrange a discreet unit to investigate.
瑞秋和我们技术团队的一位工作人员
Rachel, with a member of our technical team.
如果你愿意与我们分享任何发现
Provided you're willing to share any findings with us.
我们计划是尽快发布
We plan to run this as soon as possible.
-发布什么 -报道
- Run?  - The story.
-要报道吗 -我们清楚艾萨克·特纳昨晚不在中国
- Is there one?  - We know that Isaac Turner wasn't in China last night,
所以很明显 我们要找的是某类外国方面干涉
so clearly, we're looking at some kind of foreign interference.
我们在权衡各种理论 从黑客攻击到深伪技术
We're juggling theories, from hacking to full-on deep fakes.
值得注意的是 特纳说的正是赞达希望他说的话
It is remarkable that Turner said exactly what Xanda wanted him to.
关于那位大臣 我们有这么多可报道的事
Of all the stories on our radar involving that particular minister,
如果我是你 我会将这个搁置起来
I'd shelve this one if I were you.
因为
Because...?
因为BBC需要维护自己是
Because the BBC needs to maintain its reputation
可靠新闻来源的声誉 而不是虚假信息的灯塔
as a trusted news source, not a beacon of disinformation.
我们已经讨论过这个难题了
Yes, we've discussed this conundrum.
如果我们报道 就有可能损害我们的信誉
If we report it, we risk undermining our credibility.
但如果我们不报道 却又泄露出去了 只会更糟
But if we don't and it gets out, that would be worse.
那我就不让你们进退两难了
Then let me spare you the dilemma.
这已经引起了一些关注
Already, this raises a number of concerns.
我相信你会合作的
I'm sure I can count on your cooperation.
在我们调查期间将报道暂自搁置
Hold the story while we investigate.
前提是你要在我们调查期间
Well, so long as you can enlighten us
针对那些关注给我们些提示
on those concerns while we investigate.
恐怕不行
I'm afraid I can't do that.
那么 恐怕我不能让你在我们的工作室里打探了
Well, then, I'm afraid I can't allow you to sniff around our studio.
我们再回来就会拿上搜查令了
We'll come back with a warrant.
你刚刚警示我们怀疑有外国势力的
You've just alerted us to a suspected cyber attack
网络攻击 那你的工作室就是犯罪现场
by a foreign power. That makes your studio a crime scene.
如果我们不调查 就是玩忽职守
If we don't investigate, it'll be dereliction of duty.
会让你们更容易受到攻击
It'll leave you vulnerable to further attacks.
反正你也得不到想报道的内容
You won't get your story anyway.
此言尚早
I don't know.
IP地址加上技术人员分析
What with the IP address and the tech correspondent's analysis,
我觉得七分钟就能解决战斗
I can see seven minutes shaping up nicely.
你让我们别无选择
You're leaving us with no alternative.
你不能播
You can't broadcast it.
我们会下发国防机密通知
We'll slap a D-notice on it.
给哈迪亚·汗下发国防机密通知
A D-notice to Khadija Khan?
这不拱火呢么
Red rag, bull.
你得做更多才能拉拢她
You'll have to do more than that to bring her onside.
别这样杰姆 你知道规矩
Come on, Gem, you know the deal.
要是你打算使用核武器
If you're going to use the nuclear option,
就得给点甜头
you've got to offer up a sweetener.
你刚提到说还有其他可报道的
You mentioned other stories.
关于大臣的
About the minister.
“出于对我和我家人的安全着想”
"Fearing for my safety and the safety of my family,
“我 我决定改变对赞达面部识别的立场”
"I...I decided to alter my position on Xanda Facial Recognition."
你就给我想出这招
This is how you want me to play it -
我是被胁迫的才改了主意
that I was intimidated into changing my mind?
你得给你的员工和妻子一个解释
You need an explanation for your staff, your wife.
我不会对我妻子撒谎
I don't lie to my wife.
当然
Of course.
谢谢你能过来 大臣 请坐吧
Ah. Thanks for coming in to see us, Minister. Why don't you take a seat?
感谢你通知我最新消息 先生
I appreciate you keeping me updated, sir.
有什么新消息吗
What can you give me?
你在调查赞达 对吧
You're looking into Xanda, right?
是的 我们已开展多项调查
We are running multiple lines of inquiry, of course.
你们也跟我团队 艾丽莎·克拉克 里斯·爱德华兹谈过吧
And my team, you're talking to my team - Aliza Clark, Rhys Edwards?
他们在帮我们 谈过了
They're helping us, yeah.
内政部那边有消息吗 我是没收到
Have you heard from the Home Office? I certainly haven't.
你坐下来会更舒服些吧 大臣
Might you be more comfortable sitting down, Minister?
不 不大会 丹尼 我整晚都被关在安全屋里
No, not really, Danny. I have been cooped in a safe house all night.
我们只是想问你几个问题 先生
We just need to ask you a few questions, sir.
好
OK.
-你认识艾丽莎·克拉克多久了 -艾丽莎
- How...how long have you known Aliza Clark?  - Aliza?
昨晚我们同意接受《新闻之夜》 采访的时候
I was with Rhys and Isaac last night
我跟里斯还有艾萨克在一起
when we agreed to do the Newsnight interview.
-里斯去了 -自打我当上安全大臣之后
- Rhys went off to... - She's been with me since,
她一直跟着我 一年了
well, since I became Security Minister. A year.
你对她私生活了解多少
What do you know about her private life?
我不确定她有没有私生活 她应该养了只猫吧
I'm not sure she has one. I imagine there's a cat.
那里斯·爱德华兹呢
Hmm! What about Rhys Edwards?
我安排的采访想 跟艾萨克确认
I set up the interview, tried to confirm it with Isaac,
但是打不通 讲真 我不知道还能告诉你什么
couldn't get through. Honestly, I don't know what else to tell you.
他是个挺不错的副手 公立学校的窝囊废
He's a decent spad. He's public-school prat,
但我在政府工作 周围都是这种人
but I'm in government, I'm surrounded by them.
你知不知道有什么理由能让克拉克
Are you aware of any reason either Clark or Edwards
或爱德华兹收受贿赂
could have been compromised?
-受贿 -所有可能导致他们
- Compromised?  - Well, anything that may have left them vulnerable
受贿或被勒索的弱点
to bribery or blackmail.
英国国会里发生什么我都不会吃惊
Nothing in Westminster would surprise me,
但是 不 我什么都不知道 为什么这么问
but, no, I'm not aware of anything. Why?
对BBC的网络攻击经过精心策划
The cyberattacks on the BBC were coordinated so meticulously
也就是说你团队中有一个或多个成员被买通勾结
that it suggests the collusion of one or more members of your team.
艾丽莎和里斯
Aliza and Rhys?
或者你本人 大臣
Or indeed yourself, Minister.
我以为
I thought... Huh!
我以为我是来听最新汇报的 是怀疑到我头上了吗
I thought I was brought here for an update. Am  I  under suspicion?
在涉及外国干预的案件中
Well, with cases involving foreign intervention,
发现受害者是被胁迫的情况并不罕见
it's not unusual to find that victims have been...coerced.
勒索
Blackmailed.
关于维多利亚·贝洛 你知道些什么
What can you tell us about Victoria Bello?
所以你也认同 这么做是正确的了
Then you agree, it was the right move?
你编造了另一个故事
You planted the other story,
然后让他们以为是他们自己发现的
then let them think finding it was their idea.
你得到了我们想要的结果 长官
You got the result we needed, Ma'am.
负责英国边境的大臣
The minister in charge of Britain's borders has
有个外国私生子想成为英国人
a foreign lovechild trying to get in.
不管有没有我们的推波助澜 这个故事迟早会被曝光
That story will come out sooner or later, with or without our help.
我想是的
I imagine so.
你看过我们的电邮了吗
Have you been reading our emails?
你提供给我们的任何信息都非常有用
Any information you could provide us would be extremely helpful.
我的办公室收到了一些假报道
Er...my office received some bogus report
说一个女人声称我是她孩子的父亲 但是
about a woman claiming I'm the father of her child, but...
-都是谎言 -你怀疑幕后黑手是中国
- it's all lies.  - And you suspected China was behind it?
严王磊暗中威胁过 说要进行间谍活动
Yan Wanglei made some veiled threat about spying.
“是人就有秘密” 他这么说的 但他错了 我没有
"Everybody has something", he said, but he's wrong, I don't.
你是说他们编了个私生子出来就为了勒索你
You're saying that they made up the lovechild story to blackmail you?
或者说是诋毁我 诽谤
Or to defame me, discredit me.
中国伪造了你的声明 他们干嘛要诋毁你
China faked your announcement. Why would they want to discredit you?
我不知道 警探
I-I don't know, Detective.
我希望你们能帮我搞清楚
I'd really love to leave the job of figuring out
中国怎么搞得我 以及为什么搞我
exactly how and why China fucked us to you,
so I can get on with the job of figuring out
how the hell the Government's meant to respond.
我想我可以走了吧
I assume I'm free to leave?
只要有保护警员陪同就可以
As long as you're accompanied by protection officers.
我想问最后一个问题
Um, I'd just like to ask one last question.
你之前没提过私生子的事
You didn't mention anything about the lovechild allegation to us.
为什么
Why is that?
我没指望你能理解
I wouldn't expect you to understand.
听着 我不想这种事
Look, I don't want something like this
引起关注 即便是假的
getting traction, even false.
不能传出去
We can't have it out there.
看来我来对地方了
I guess I'm in the right place.
我还挺希望是你来呢
I was hoping it would be you.
瑞秋 这是路易
Rachel, Louie.
弗兰克让我提醒你限制参数
Frank told me to remind you of the parameters.
弗兰克需要的是放个假
Frank needs a fucking holiday.
我从没这么久不使用手机
That is the longest I've been without my phone.
-打什么时候开始算起 -没了 那句话说完了
- Since?  - No, that was the end of my sentence.
-那么 -有多糟
- So, what - how bad is it?
"艾萨克态度大转变"显然上了热搜
Er...well, "Isaac U-turn" is obviously trending.
骂声一片
There's no shortage of hate.
但在这之前很多人 都不知道你是谁 所以
But until now, a lot of these people didn't know who you were, so...
支持率下降 品牌知名度上升
Approval ratings down, brand awareness up.
就是这种弱鸡程度
You know, it's this level of incompetence
让我相信你们两个都没有参与
that reassures me neither of you are involved.
首相怎么说 发表声明了吗 还是
What about the PM - any statement, or...?
-唐宁街和内政部都没表态 -没表态
- Nothing from Downing Street or the Home Office.  - Nothing?
等等 麦肯齐留了语音留言
Oh, wait, there's a voice message from McKenzie.
《新闻之夜》想今晚采访你
Newsnight want you back on tonight.
怎么 你想说什么 艾丽莎
What? What do you want to say, Aliza?
我觉得我们都想知道发生了什么
I think we'd all just like to know what happened.
你有一条新消息
You have one new message...
出于对我和我家人的安全着想
Fearing for my safety and the safety of my family,
我决定改变对赞达面部识别的立场
I decided to alter my position on Xanda Facial Recognition.
我就知道 这就说得通了 艾萨克
I knew it. It's fair enough, Isaac.
怎么了 你不懂 你又没孩子
Hmm!  What? YOU don't know. YOU don't have kids.
你不也没有吗 除非有私生子的那个人是你
Well, neither do you, unless YOU'RE the one with the secret lovechild.
抱歉 假的私生子
Sorry, fake secret lovechild.
这是另一件事 他们也知道了
That's the other thing, they know about that, too.
不止他们知道
They're not the only ones.
你早餐吃了什么 艾萨克
What did you have for breakfast, Isaac?
很久以前的事了我不记得了
It was so long ago, I can't remember.
谢谢 音量正常
Thank you. Audio level's good.
你一般都会做录音测试吗
Do you normally do test recordings?
每次连新的计算机或者换新地方的时侯会测
Whenever we link up to a new computer or a new location.
他手下说艾萨克·特纳想做远程采访的时候
When his spad said that Isaac Turner wanted to do a remote interview,
我以为他是说在家里接受来访
I assumed he meant from home.
但后来特纳打来说他在伦敦
But then Turner called and said he was in London.
艾萨克·特纳亲自打给你
Isaac Turner called you himself?
对
Yes.
他听起来什么样
And how did he sound?
艾萨克·特纳那样
Like Isaac Turner.
-所以 没什么不一样的吗 -没
- So, nothing unusual?  - No.
我们把链接发给他 他直接就开始测音了
We sent him the link and he jumped straight on this test.
他确实有点像克里斯蒂安·贝尔
He did get a bit Christian Bale at one point.
你能把笔记本电脑抬高一英寸吗 艾萨克
Any chance you could raise your laptop an inch for me, Isaac?
不能 现在这个画面我挺满意的
No, I'm pretty happy with the frame.
嗯 我们想后面留白多一些
Yeah, well, we'd prefer a bit more headroom.
要不取消采访吧
Or we can cancel the interview.
他决定的取景范围
He chose the framing.
对 架子大得很
Yeah. Diva.
聪明
Smart.
你能透露点什么吗 私下里说
So, what can you tell us, off the record?
是不是中国方面黑了我的程序 还是怎么的
Did China hack my programme, or what?
随便你问 艾德 你不会得到任何答案的
You can ask all you like, Ed, you won't get any answers.
-哈迪亚 这是 -瑞秋
- Khadija. Er...this is...  - Rachel.
Hmm.
安东尼跟我说你会四处打探
Anthony told me you'd be sniffing around.
如果你能抽出几分钟时间 我会非常感激 汗小姐
Well, I'd appreciate a few minutes, Miss Khan, when you can spare them.
你不让我报道之前就应该想到这点
You should've thought of that before you took my story away.
我们在调查一个更棒的新闻
We're working on a better one.
嗯 拭目以待
Yeah, we'll see.
她是慢热型
She'll warm up, possibly.
所以你要报道私生子的事喽
You're running it, then, the love child story?
对 得先核实一下
Yeah. We need to verify it first.
失陪
Excuse me.
-汤姆 -医院那边应该是有好消息
- Tom.  - Looks like there's good news from the hospital.
我这就过去
I'm heading over there.
我昨天问过你 有什么我应该知道的事
I asked you yesterday, was there anything I should know.
当时没有 现在也没有
There was nothing then, there's nothing now.
BBC要求发表评论 跟他们说都是瞎扯
The BBC are asking for a comment. Tell them it's bullshit,
要是他们报道 我们就大幅度削减他们预算
and if they run it, we'll take a pickaxe to their budget.
在走到那步之前 艾萨克
Well, before we go that route, Isaac,
有件事我们得问问你
there is something we need to ask you.
真的吗
Is it?
Bullshit?
这故事可信度极高
It's a perfectly plausible story.
四年前你在拉各斯
You were in Lagos four years ago.
显然有人做足了功课
Somebody's obviously done their homework.
这么看 你做的也挺足的
So have you, by the looks of it.
你没查出来我为什么去吗
You manage to uncover WHY I was there?
不知道 我飞去拉各斯参加我母亲的葬礼
No? I flew to Lagos for my mother's funeral.
很好 不是很好 节哀顺变
Good! Um...not good. I'm sorry for your loss.
都过去四年了 罗文
It was four years ago, Rowan.
你愿意做亲子鉴定吗
Would you be willing to take a paternity test?
真服了 人家刚跟你说他去给他母亲送葬了
For God's sake, the man's just told you he was burying his mother!
-情绪上头嘛 -什么意思
- An emotional time. - What does that mean?
就是说你飞去拉各斯
It means it's not impossible that while you flew to Lagos
给你母亲下葬那次 也在某时常刻埋下了
to bury your mother, you did also at some point during that trip
其他东西
bury something else.
四年前 我们刚刚赢得选举
Four years ago, we'd just won the election.
你真觉得我会在刚拿到议会席位的同时
Do you really think I'd jeopardise my seat in Parliament
-干出危及地位的事吗 -是人都会出错 你错了
- when I'd only just taken it?  - We all fuck up.  That's where you're wrong.
-你没出错吗 -没
- You don't fuck up?  - No.
那我就告诉媒体 这不可能是真的
So I'll just tell the press that it can't be true,
因为出色的艾萨克·特纳绝不会出错
because the amazing Isaac Turner never fucks up!
我问你件事
Let me ask you something.
有多少内阁大臣被抓到下不来台的场面
How many Cabinet ministers get caught with their pants down
或者为了东山再起
or their fingers in the expenses pot
监守自盗 职业生涯毫发无损
only to bounce right back, careers unscathed?
你看 如果你像我一样 那就不太管用了
You see, it doesn't quite work like that if you look like me.
如果我不诚实或滥交
If I'M dishonest or promiscuous,
我只会证实了大家最坏的怀疑
I'm just confirming everybody's worst suspicions.
所以我父母告诉我要加倍努力
So there's a reason my parents told me to work twice as hard
表现得比学校里其他孩子好一倍
and act twice as nice as all the other kids in school.
我遵从了他们的建议 现在仍在践行
I took their advice, I'm still taking it now.
我尊重我的妻子和孩子
I treat my wife and children with respect,
但我这么做不是为了他们 也不是因为这样就是个
but I don't do it just for their sake or because it makes me
好的基督徒 不管大家怎么想
a good Christian, despite what everybody thinks.
我这么做是因为没人会给我第二次机会
I do it because no-one's going to give me a second chance!
所以 不会 当我要在英国国会成功的时候
So, no, when it comes to getting ahead in Westminster,
我不会出错的
I don't fuck up.
我会跟BBC说不要报道
I'll tell the BBC to bury the story.
真他妈谢谢了
Thank fuck for that.
内政大臣 我想单独跟你谈谈
Home Secretary, I'd like a word, alone.
高危病房
..High Dependency Unit,
也就是说他的状态很不好 但已经渡过了危机关头
which means his condition is serious, but no longer critical.
他现在出于药物造成的昏迷之中
He's in a medically induced coma,
但是他会醒过来的
but he will wake in due course.
他会好起来吗
Is he going to be all right?
会的
Yeah.
爸爸还在睡觉 但他会好起来的
Daddy's still sleeping, but he's going to be all right.
-我们去看看他好不好 -嗯
- OK.  Shall we go and see him?  - Yeah.
医生 他还有多久能恢复意识
Doctor? How long do you think before he's conscious?
每个病人都不一样 但是
Well, each patient is different, but, er...
-他也许几小时后就能醒过来 -谢谢
- well, he could be awake in the next couple of hours.  - Thank you.
-汤姆在 -高危病房 我们已经知道了 凯莉
- Tom is on the...  - High Dependency ward. We're way ahead of you, Carey.
艾德 数据源查的怎么样了
Ed, how's the feed check?
-K3 我是K6 -请说
- Kilo Six, Kilo Three?  - Go ahead.
我们通过控制中心在查监控 K3 一切都在计划中
We're running camera checks via Control, Kilo Three. All in order.
明白了
Understood.
看到你笑真好
Nice to see you smiling.
真会说
Whatever.  Hmm!
需要支援吗 K3
Need support to cover, Kilo Three?
我会留在这 等到帕特里克醒过来
I'm going to stay till Patrick wakes up.
-我希望他指认枪手时能在他身边 -了解
- I want to be here when he IDs the shooter.  - Understood.
嗨 我 我想买玩具 给一个两岁和一个九岁的孩子
Hi. I-I need a toy for a two-year-old and a...nine-year-old.
你他妈想干嘛
What the fuck do YOU want?
你怎么在这
What are YOU doing here?
What am I DOING here?
这他妈是家医院
It's a fucking hospital.
你得原谅我 内务大臣
You're going to have to forgive me, Home Secretary,
但是我从没研究过「移花接木」
but I've never had to navigate around Correction before.
我不知道该怎么做
I've no idea how it works.
伯我希望你或者首相可以发表个声明
But I was expecting to see a statement from you or the PM.
对于我所宣布的让人吃惊的消息给出点反应
Some reaction to my highly-surprising announcement.
但什么都没有
There's been nothing.
毕竟还在调查 现阶段是很敏感的
Well, it's sensitive whilst the investigation's ongoing.
那怎么着 就让这虚假消息继续发酵吗
Oh, what, so, we're just supposed to let the disinformation fester?
如果我们不出声
As long as we keep quiet,
大家就都以为我们还会选择赞达
everyone's going to assume we're going with Xanda.
北京得到他们想要的
Beijing gets what it wants.
你可以直接否决我的推荐
You know, you COULD overrule my recommendation.
至少签署个声明
At least issue a statement,
说你犹像不决并对此存疑
say you're undecided and introduce doubt.
你说的这些早就讨论过了
Well, those options are already being discussed.
-跟谁 -当然是首相
- With who?  - The PM, of course.
你召开了首脑会议
You called a Cobra meeting?
我们在公园里一起吃冰淇淋来着 这有什么关系吗
We met in the park for an ice cream. What difference does it make?
我要跟首相通话
I'm talking to the PM.
罗文 你看哈 这场危机是因我而起
Look, Rowan, given how central I am to this crisis,
因此我觉得自己必须全面积极的
I strongly feel I should be fully, actively involved
参与到收府的回复中去
in the Government's response.
我觉得你现在最需要的是好好休息
I think you deserve a bloody good rest, mate.
我不需要休息
I don't NEED a rest.
英国遭受了袭击
The UK is under attack.
我不只是安全大臣 我也是他们袭击的目标之一
Not only am I Security Minister, I'm one of the targets!
所以你才要保持一个合适的安全距离
And that's all the more reason for you to maintain a healthy distance.
回家去吧 艾萨克
Go home, Isaac.
跟家人在一起
Be with your family.
好吗
All right?
艾萨克
Isaac?
是我打给《新闻之夜》告诉他们我有独家要给他们
Yes. Er...call Newsnight and tell them I've got an exclusive.
-今晚吗 -对 今晚
- Tonight?  - Yeah, tonight.
还有 莱斯 这次要确保现场直播
And, Rhys? This time, make sure it's live in the studio.
好的 我来处理
OK, I'll get right on it.
看看他啊 还有个长毛尾巴呢
Look at him. Hasn't he got a furry tail!
-长官 -你还在英国广播公司吗
- Ma'am.  - Are you still at the BBC?
不太远
Not far away.
Get back there.
艾萨克·特纳刚刚甩掉了安保人员
Isaac Turner's just cut his protection officers loose.
他要上《新闻之夜》
He's booked himself on Newsnight.
他说了什么
What did he say?
他说会是个重大新闻
He's promised them a bombshell.
他要曝光「移花接木」
He's going to expose Correction.
No. You're going to stop him.
我马上去
I'm on my way.
如果里面的特工有苏醒迹象
Any sign of the asset waking up,
或者突然惊醒 用2号频道呼叫我
he so much as stirs in his sleep, radio me on Two.
是 长官
Yes, Ma'am.
独家新闻 他就只说了这么多
An exclusive - that's all he's prepared to tell us upfront.
如果是有关黑客入侵的事呢
What if it's about the hack?
安东尼已经担保过不会声张了
Well, Anthony gave the service his word,
但如果艾萨克·特纳自己说出来
but if it comes from Isaac Turner...
那就怪不得别人了
..then that's on him.
真搞笑
Fucking tease!
我都开始喜欢他了
I'm starting to like him!  Ha!
特纳先生
Mr Turner!
特纳先生 你不能这么做
Mr Turner, this is not the way!
-你不能就 -还有两分钟 大臣
- You can't just...! - Two minutes, Minister.
-我 -他们为了保护消息不外传甚至不惜杀人
- I...  - They kill people to protect it.
你在给我做「移花接木」的简报时我见过你
I saw you when you briefed me on Correction.
你是 你不是他们那边的对吧
You're...you're not a true believer, are you?
你需要小心
You need to be careful.
需要先制定个计划
You need a plan.
如果你想曝光一件事 就不能随便上电视说
If you want to expose this thing, you can't just go on TV and say it.
我没打算说
I wasn't going to.
-我以为 -他们杀了谁
- I thought...  - Who have they killed?
大臣先生 您可以跟我过来了
If you'd like to follow me, Minister?
你莫非有什么好计划吗
Have YOU got a plan to expose it?
大臣
Minister?
长官 局面控制住了
Ma'am. It's under control.
-你阻止他了 -没有
- You stopped him?  - No.
你让他继续了
You let him go on?
他跟我说不会讲「移花接木」的事
H's not going to talk about Correction, he told me.
你信了
And you trust him?
是的
Yes.
首先是#家庭作业# 然后在中国事件上又出现了令人吃惊的反转
First #homework, then a startling U-turn on China.
现在 安全大臣艾萨克·特纳又要发布消息了
Now Security Minister Isaac Turner is set to make headlines again.
Newsnight theme tune
为什么我不知道这事
Why was I not told about this?
我也不知道啊
Why wasn't  I  told about it?!
48小时前 你们可能有人
48 hours ago, some of you might have struggled to name
还说不出英国安全大臣的名字
the UK's Security Minister,
但48小时可以发生很多事
but a lot can happen in 48 hours,
正如艾萨克·特纳要说的一样
as Isaac Turner can tell you.
-晚上好 哈迪亚 -是您主动联系的我们对吧
- Good evening, Khadija.  - You contacted us before we went on air
说你要在现场直播时做一个非常重要的声明
with what you said would be a revelatory statement.
是的 抱歉 鉴于一些秘密行动的缘故
Yes. Apologies, Khadija, for the cloak and dagger.
我必须确保 所说的话
I just wanted to make sure
能够通过一个畅通的渠道传达给大众
I had a clear channel for what I'm about to say.
有关昨天的声明 我要进行修正
Regarding yesterday's announcement, I'd like to make a correction.
事实是 我不支持赞达公司
The fact is, I do NOT support Xanda's bid
参与英国边境面部识别的投标
to supply facial rec at Britain's borders.
你又改变了主意是吗
You've changed your mind again?
我 我不支持他们的投标 并且我强烈建议
Er...I-I do not support their bid, and I strongly recommend
政府不要考虑中国公司
the Government considers options outside of China.
-昨天你还说没什么好担心的 -我的天
- Yesterday, you said there was nothing to fear from...  - Oh, my God!
中国的技术在
..the use of Chinese technology
-英国的基础设施中使用 -我 我 我来这不是为了辩驳
- in UK infrastructure. - I-I-I didn't come here to dwell on
我说了什么或者没说什么
what I did or didn't say.
-我只是直接引用了你说的 -不管怎么说吧 边境问题
- That was a direct quote.  - Well, nonetheless, the issue of borders...
面部侧写可确保我们安保系统行之有效
..Facial profiling is what makes us the most effective security system.
-我的天 -不 不 不
- Oh, my God!  - No, no, no!
-你不是在开玩笑吧 -但如果
- You've got to be fucking joking. - ..But if, say,
17-35岁的穆斯林男性
Muslim men between the ages of 17 and 35...
最有可能对机场进行袭击
were the most-likely demographic to launch an attack on an airport...
一个那样的系统
..what's wrong with
-能有什么 -我宁愿面对
- a system that...? - I'd rather face the consequences
自己突然改变口径的后果
of appearing to change course
也不想看到赞达公司接手我们边境的面部识别项目
than face the prospect of Xanda's facial rec at our borders.
让一家与中国共产党有关系的公司
Giving a firm with links to the Chinese Communist Party
接入我们的监控网络将享有这些侧写
access to our surveillance networks would constitute...
赞达公司的确颇有卖点
..Profiling, Xanda treats it as a selling point.
一个卖点
A selling point?
-改变了你的主意 -我一直担心有些不正当压力
- ..Changed your mind? - I've always been concerned about undue influence of...
首相不支持你的报告吗
Did the Prime Minister not back your report?
将报告
Putting together the CRC...
与任何拥有国际云的公司一样
..Like any company with an international cloud,
赞达与全球越来越多的政府保持同步
Xanda is in sync with the growing number of governments
他们对此想法没有异议
around the globe who have no quarrel with the idea...
我已经决定向内阁建议
I've reached my decision to recommend to the Cabinet
面部识别合约
that the facial-recognition contract
应该给到那些科技公司
is awarded to a technology company whose...
不要再进行直播了 切断信号
Stop this broadcast! Cut it!
-艾德 你需要停止直播 -什么 不可能 去你的吧
- Ed, you need to terminate this broadcast!  - What? No! Fuck off!
赞达的技术给人一种舒适感
The fact that Xanda's maths adds up ought to be a source of comfort.
我敢确定你们大多数人会同意这一点的
I'm sure the majority of your viewers would agree.
-见鬼了 -这涉及到国家安全问题
- Fucking hell!  - This is a national security issue!
赶紧停止直播
Somebody needs to stop this broadcast!
来个人把这女的给我赶出去
Can someone get this woman out of my fucking gallery?
-我正在努力呢 -国家安全部的 赶紧停止直播
- I'm trying.  - National security. Somebody stop broadcast now!
-给我个答案 -停不了
- ..Give me an answer!  - It won't cut!
停不下来 锁定了特纳 怎么回事
It's not cutting!  We're locked on Turner!  What's going on?
面部识别可以让某个年龄段的穆斯林人
Racial profiling is what makes Muslim men between the ages of...
赞达同步于越来越
Xanda is in synch with the growing number of...
收尾 哈迪亚 别让他再说了
Wrap it up, Khadija.  Cut it back!
-哈迪亚 收尾 -大臣 我们得进行下一个话题了
- Khadija, wrap it up now. - Minister, we have to move on.
在我们的索尔福德演播室听的是
Now, listening to that in our Salford studio was...
什么鬼
What the fuck...?!
Oh.
首相
Prime Minister.
-艾德 -推特已经爆了
- Ed?  - Twitter's blown up.
什么 我们这个反转的新闻吗 不可能吧
What?! Over the U-turn? That's ludicrous!
长官 你得过来一趟
Ma'am, you need to get down here.
-为什么我老婆打过来7次 -所有人安静
- Why has my wife called seven times? - Everybody, quiet!
这是警方在办案
This is a police matter!
在有进一步指示之前谁都不许离开演播室
Nobody is to leave this studio until otherwise instructed.
我需要你 还有你
I need you...and you.
你在自播前联系的我们
You contacted us before we went on air
说你会有重大声明
with what you said would be a revelatory statement.
-这怎么了 -继续看
- What's wrong with this?! - Keep watching.
有关昨天的声明 我需要做个修正
Regarding yesterday's announcement, I'd like to make a correction.
你问过我 赞达是否已经进行了测试
You asked me if Xanda had been tested for racial bias.
我的回答恐怕不是非常准确
I'm afraid my answer wasn't entirely accurate.
这是什么 他没说这个啊
What IS this? He didn't say that.
事实是
The truth is,
赞达做的面部识别系统是市场上
racial profiling is what makes Xanda
最有效的系统
the most-effective security system on the market.
-什么 -我们被黑了 内容被更改了 都是假的
- What?!  - We've been hacked. This has been changed! Faked!
被「移花接木」了
Corrected.
如果 当然我不是说就是这样哈
If, and I'm not saying this is the case,
但如果 17-35岁的穆斯林男性
but if, say, Muslim men between the ages of 17 and 35
最有可能对机场进行袭击
were the most-likely demographic to launch an attack at an airport,
一个把这一点纳入考虑的系统有什么问题呢
what's wrong with a system that factors that in?
我我我我 我不可能会
I-I-I-I-I would...I would nev...
-怎么会这样 -我不知道
- H-How...?  - I don't know.
大臣先生 你是在建议
Minister, are you suggesting
该计划故意引入了种族歧视吗
the programme uses racial bias deliberately...?
-那是我的声音 -我不是在建议 我只是说哈
- That's my voice! - I'm not suggesting, I'm saying.
虽然大多数面部识别提供商
While most facial-recognition providers
将侧写视为人工智能缺陷
see profiling as an AI flaw,
赞达却将其视为一个卖点
Xanda treats it as a selling point.
-一个卖点 -是的
- A selling point?  - Yes.
跟其它公司一样
Like any company...
如果你认为可以发布英国国防机密通知 你得再想一下才行了
If you think you can slap a D-notice on this, you can think again.
-我需要你坐下 -你试试
- I must ask you to sit down. - Good luck with that!
-你是破坏国家安全事件的目击证人 -开什么玩笑
You are a witness to a major national security breach.  No shit!
-第一次 人们要 -每个人都是嫌疑人
- First time...  - Everyone here is a suspect...
-别再让我解释了 -另外 我必须
- Do not make me explain... - Furthermore, I must...
在这个时间和其他嫌疑人进行交流
..Choosing to interact with other suspects at this time
可能会影响到反恐调查
may compromise a counter-terror investigation!
-抱歉 我可不管其他人怎么样 -哈迪亚
- Sorry, I'm going way above anyone in here.  - Khadija!
也许我们该让她走
Maybe we should let her get on with it.
我跟你说了 没那么简单
I told you, it is not that simple!
我也问过了 你是不是有什么好计划
And I asked you if you had a plan!
等在这
Wait here.
-大臣 可不可以理解为 -我可以告诉你
- Minister... to be completely clear,  - I can tell you that...
你提倡在英国机场使用种族定性
you're advocating the use of racial profiling at UK airports?
不是的 哈迪亚 我说清楚一点
No, Khadija, to be completely clear,
只要能保证我们的国土安全 我就建议使用种族定性
I'm advocating the use of racial profiling wherever it keeps us safe.
-大臣 我们得继续下一个话题了 -我完蛋了
- Minister, we have to move on. - I'm fucking finished.
哈迪亚
Khadija?
-哈迪亚 -你不能抢走我的报道
- Khadija!  - You are not taking this story away from me.
我要打给渠道控制部和法务部
I'm calling the channel controller and then I'm calling legal.
信号他妈的怎么回事
Fucking signal!
你打算怎么证明呢
And how are you going to prove it?
我亲眼见到自己的现场报道被人黑入 并用虚假信息取代了
I just saw myself hacked and deep-faked with my own eyes!
可所有人看到的今晚的专访跟前几天晚上的都是一样的
And everybody else saw an interview, just like every other night.
你一个人的证词对阵所有人的
It will be your word against everybody else's.
甚至连工作人员都没看到发生了什么
Not even your own crew saw what happened!
你不知道自己对付的是什么人
You have no idea what you're up against.
如果你真的在乎调查 并且想曝光这件事
If you're serious about investigating it and exposing it...
喂
Hello?
你需要先取得证据
..you need to gather evidence meticulously.
很多证据才行
A wealth of it.
你需要确实证明这件事
You need to prove it definitively
这样没人可以否认
so no-one can deny it.
喂
Hello?
谁啊
Who is it?
那你建议我该怎么做
And how do you suggest doing that?
加入我们Together.